{
  "reference_number": "12995",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Before taking any action to interfere with the national economy or the lifestyle of its citizens, the government should provide\n\n irrefutable proof that human production of carbon dioxide in New Zealand is harmful to humans or any other lifeforms in New Zealand.\n Any action should be weighed against the cost of adapting to climate change, and the need to improve resilience to cope with\n temperature decrease."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Disengage from the globalist Marxist scam."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "What sort of nutcases would specify “no”? Oh right, the ones we have in government."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The welfare of New Zealand’s environment economy and people. The $1.4b pa would be much better spent protecting EEZ and\n\nrestoring waterways."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "About 13 years ago I wrote a series of columns in The Gisborne Herald expressing doubt about the validity of the famed “hockey stick\n\ngraph” as a predictor of future climate. Time has vindicated my cynicism - a result of a university degree in Earth Sciences. Virtually all\nclimate models have grossly over-estimated warming yet as a nation we are still following this international Marxist scam. Adaptation\n\nto inevitable climate change, including likely cooling, is a far more sensible approach, but that won’t help our treacherous politicians\nand technocrats secure lucrative roles at the UN."
    }
  ]
}
